[MUSIC]
[음악]
We've done now some simple regression, some simple regression for
전용면적 데이터를 통해 간단한 회귀분석을
our data just using square foot of living.
해보았습니다
But if you remember, our data set had many other columns associated with that, or
하지만 데이터 세트에는 다른 열과 특징도
features.
가지고 있는 경우입니다
So what we're gonna do next is
다음으로는
explore other features in the data.
데이터의 다른 특징을 탐구합니다
So let's do some exploration of other possible features we might use.
쓸만한 다른 특징을 탐구해보죠
So I'm going to use a set of features.
특징 세트를 이용할 겁니다
So let's create a list of the features I'm going to explore, the code features.
탐구할 특징의 목록에 특징이란 이름을 붙입니다
And these features are going to be the number
이 특징들은 침실의 개수,
of bedrooms, the number of bathrooms.
화장실 개수
Let's see, what else?
보자, 뭐가 또 있죠?
The square foot of living space, which is what we've been exploring so far.
전용면적은 우리가 지금까지 했었죠
In addition to this, I'm going to include the square foot of the lot, so
추가로 주택 토지의 넓이인 대지면적을
this is how much land the house has all around it.
포함시키겠습니다
The number of floors in the house.
주택의 층수
And finally, I'm gonna include a variable called the ZIP code.
마지막으로 ZIP코드라는 변수를 포함합니다
And so the ZIP code in
미국의 ZIP코드는
the United States is what other countries call the postal code.
다른 나라에서는 우편번호라 불리죠
In Brazil we call this SAPI.
브라질에서는 CEP라고 합니다
But there are many names in different places, that's what we'll include.
여러 곳에서 서로 다르게 불리는데 아무튼 이걸 추가합니다
So, let's see, if I take the sales data and I just select this column,
판매 데이터에서 특징 열을 선택하는데
just select the features column here, why don't we call them just to be totally
잠시 여기 특징 이름을 my_features라고
clear, instead of calling them features I'm going to call them my_features.
명확하게 하죠
Shift+Enter.
쉬프트+엔터
And then I'm gonna look at what my_features columns look like.
그리고 my_features 열을 살펴보면 이렇습니다
So I'm gonna type .show.
.show를 입력합니다
Remember, we can type .show anything with GraphLab Create.
GraphLab Create에서는 무엇이든 끝에 .show를 입력할 수 있는거 아시죠
On the sframe for sales, selecting the my_features.
판매 SFrame에서 my_features을 선택하는거죠
And now we're gonna have a visualization of these features.
특징들이 시각화된 모습이 나타납니다
So let me just walk you through this visualization.
시각화된 특징을 차근차근 짚어보겠습니다
Get my mouse here.
마우스를 가져다 댑니다
So bedrooms, let's look at frequency.
침실의 빈도를 봅시다
There are 13 different unique types.
13종류가 있군요
In fact, there's some houses with ten bedrooms.
어떤 집들은 침실이 열 개네요
Most houses have three bedrooms.
대부분은 세 개입니다
Some have four, some have two, some have five, and very few have more.
몇몇은 네 개, 몇몇은 두 개, 몇몇은 다섯 개, 소수는 그 이상군요
With bathrooms,
화장실로는
it turns out that house in the US, you have fractional number of bathrooms.
미국에서는 분수로 된 화장실을 가질 수도 있군요
When you say, for example, 2.5 bathrooms is the most common number,
훑어보면 화장실 2.5개가 가장 흔한데
it's because if you have a house with a bathroom with a bath in it,
화장실에 욕조가 있으면
it's called a full bath, it counts for 1.
완전하니 하나로 치고
But if you have just a bathroom that has a sink and a toilet, it's just worth 0.5.
싱크대와 변기만 있으면 0.5개로 칩니다
And so here you have 2.5.
이렇게 해서 2.5개가 되는 것이죠
In fact, if you have a bathroom with a sink, a toilet, and
사실 화장실에 싱크대, 변기,
a shower, but no tub, that's worth 0.75 in the US.
샤워실이 있고 욕조가 없으면 미국에서는 0.75개로 칩니다
So there you go.
자, 여기 있죠.
That's where you can have one bathroom is the second most common, and
화장실 한 개가 두 번째로 흔하고
then you have this 1.75 bathroom, which is probably
그 다음이 1.75개인데 아마
going to be one full bath with a bath and a bathroom with a shower.
다 갖춘 화장실 하나에 샤워실까지만 있는 게 하나일테죠
And you can see the distribution here.
분포를 봅니다
Similarly for other things, like square foot of living, and
다른 특징과 유사하게 전용면적, 층수
number of floors, most houses have one floor, some have two.
대부분은 일층이고 이층집도 몇 있죠
And then the ZIP code.
그리고 우편번호입니다
The most common zipcode is 98103,
가장 많은 건 98103인데
which is an area where a lot of people live in Seattle.
시애틀의 인구가 집중된 지역이죠
Okay, so
이제
we've seen a high level visualization of the different columns of the data.
데이터의 여러 열에 대한 고도의 시각화를 구경했으니
Now let's look at some other relationships of the data.
데이터의 다른 관련성도 살펴볼 차례입니다
Let's do some fun visualizations here.
재밌는 시각화를 한번 해보죠
So I'm gonna take the sales table and I'm gonna type show.
판매표에 .show를 입력합니다
But the view that I'm gonna do, it's not gonna be scatterplot.
하지만 산점도 뷰를 보는 게 아닙니다
But it's gonna be what is called a box whisker plot, and
상자 그림이라 불리는 게 될텐데
this box whisker plot is gonna relate two variables that we looked at.
상자 그림은 두 변수의 관계를 설명합니다
On the x side, I'm gonna use the ZIP code, so this is the postal code
x축에는 우편번호를 씁니다
that we discussed, and on the y-axis, I'm going to plot the price.
y축에는 가격을 그립니다
So what we're gonna see is the relationship between the location,
그러면 우편번호로 표현되는 위치와 가격의
the ZIP code, where the house is, and the price.
관련성을 보게 됩니다
And we're gonna see that with what's called a box whisker plot.
박스 그림을 통해 보게 됩니다
So I'm gonna press Shift+Enter and we're gonna plot it.
쉬프트+엔터를 눌러 그립니다
And here's what we'll see.
이런 화면을 보게 됩니다
So you will see, for example,
직접 볼 수 있듯이
this area's zip code, post code,
이 지역 우편번호인 98003에서는
98003, has a significantly lower price.
가격이 상당히 낮습니다
So the average price is low, that's the red line, and not a lot of variability.
빨간선으로 표현되는 평균 가격이 낮고 변동성이 크지 않습니다
While this other zip code 98004, so this is 003,
98004 같은 우편번호는
98004, has a highest average price, much higher,
가장 높은 평균 가격인데
1 point something million, 1.1 million, and a huge variability.
100만 달러가 넘고 110만 정도에 변동성이 엄청납니다
So the houses range from something like, what is this?
적게는 어디죠
$800,000, it's almost $4 million.
80만 달러에서 거의 400만 달러까지 다양합니다
But here I'm just showing a few ZIP codes.
이건 처음 몇 개만 보여드린 거고요
If I drag down here, you'll see more and more ZIP codes.
이쪽으로 당기면 더 많은 우편번호를 볼 수 있습니다
And wow, what is this one over here?
와, 여기 이건 뭐죠?
There's one that's astronomical, it goes out of the scale.
어마어마한 게 하나가 혼자만 따로 노네요
Some houses here cost like, what is this?
이쪽 집들은 대충 얼마죠?
$7 million or something.
700만 달러쯤 되겠군요
And this post code is 98039.
우편번호는 98039입니다
Remember 98039, we'll come back to it at the end of this notebook.
98039 기억해 두세요 이 노트북 끝 무렵에 다시 보겠습니다
It's kind of funny.
재밌군요
[MUSIC]
[음악]